Hello again, welcome to the second module of course number five.
In this module, we will look into Hyperparameter Tuning.
Just to recap, in previous module,
we talked about the Art of ML.
We looked into regularisation and optimization techniques,
and learn how our model performance can be sensitive to batch size and learning rate.
We experimented with adjusting
those Hyperparameters manually to improve model performance.
In this module, you'll learn how to differentiate between parameters and Hyperparameters.
We will review some of the important ones,
then we'll discuss traditional grid search approach,
and learn how to think beyond that,
with the smarter algorithms.
Finally, you'll learn how Cloud ML Engine,
makes it so convenient to automate Hyperparameter Tuning.
Sounds good. Let's get started.