In this Lab, you will clone
the GitHub repository of the course within your Datalab instance,
and save it all in your project.
And then, you can work with a notebook to try out the machine learning APIs.
As before, the Labs often have you simply run through a workout example.
Because we cannot help you personally debug your code,
we're choosing to do it this way.
To make sure you understand what is being done though,
try changing the code and see if you understand the impact of those changes.
Ultimately, remove the code from a critical section of the notebook.
The critical sections are often pointed out in the challenge sections of the Labs,
and see if you can write the code yourself.
And if you get stuck,
look back at the solution.