Welcome back.
Here, we will introduce you to the core components of
TensorFlow and get hands on practice building machine learning programs.
Most TensorFlow production programs work in a lazy evaluation mode.
Although, you might find yourself developing
your programs in eager mode, which is imperative.
You will learn what I mean when I say lazy evaluation imperative,
and learn how to write lazy evaluation and imperative programs.
Lazy evaluation means that TensorFlow works of
variables that are parts of graphs that are tied to sessions.
You will learn what these concepts mean and how to
work with graphs, sessions, and variables.
Understanding how well a machine learning model is doing will require you to views
KLR numbers like losses and weights over the course of training as a chart.
You also typically want to look at things called embeddings,
or projectors, and the architecture of your model.
In this chapter, you will also learn how to visualize TensorFlow graphs.
Finally, things aren't always smooth and easy.
When you're writing code,
you will run into programs that don't compile or worse,
programs that crash on some specific data input.
So, you will learn how to debug TensorFlow programs.