Hi, I'm Josh Cogan.
I'm a software engineer at Google.
Today, I'm excited to talk to
you about how Google does ML.
This talk is about the organizational
know-how we've acquired over the years,
as we have built probably more
value-generating ML systems than any other
company.
This is a topic that I know first-hand,
from my work on Google's own systems, and
as an adviser to many companies as
they've made the transition to using
machine learning to address
their core business problems.
This probably isn't
the talk you're expecting.
There's no math, there's no TensorFlow,
there's not even any cloud.
For the next little bit, we're
going to put on our business hats and
look at ML the way the owner of
a business or someone responsible for
setting its direction would.