SPEAKER: Let's play a game.
Close your eyes
and picture a shoe.
OK.
Did anyone picture this?
This?
How about this?
We may not even know
why, but each of us
is biased toward one
shoe over the others.
Now, imagine that you're
trying to teach a computer
to recognize a shoe.
You may end up exposing
it to your own bias.
That's how bias happens
in machine learning.
But first, what is
machine learning?
Well, it's used in a lot
of technology we use today.
Machine learning helps us
get from place to place,
gives us suggestions,
translates stuff, even
understands what you say to it.
How does it work?
With traditional
programming, people
hand code the solution to
a problem, step by step.
With machine learning,
computers learn the solution
by finding patterns
in data, so it's
easy to think there's
no human bias in that.
But just because
something is based on data
doesn't automatically
make it neutral.
Even with good intentions,
it's impossible to separate
ourselves from our
own human biases,
so our human biases become
part of the technology
we create in many
different ways.
There's interaction bias,
like this recent game
where people were asked to
draw shoes for the computer.
Most people drew ones like this.
So as more people
interacted with the game,
the computer didn't
even recognize these.
Latent bias-- for example, if
you were training a computer
on what a physicist looks
like, and you're using pictures
of past physicists,
your algorithm
will end up with a latent
bias skewing towards men.
And selection bias-- say
you're training a model
to recognize faces.
Whether you grab images from
the internet or your own photo
library, are you
making sure to select
photos that represent everyone?
Since some of our most advanced
products use machine learning,
we've been working to
prevent that technology
from perpetuating
negative human bias--
from tackling offensive
or clearly misleading
information from appearing
at the top of your search
results page to adding a
feedback tool in the search bar
so people can flag
hateful or inappropriate
autocomplete suggestions.
It's a complex issue, and
there is no magic bullet,
but it starts with all
of us being aware of it,
so we can all be part
of the conversation,
because technology
should work for everyone.