Now that we've learned about [inaudible] regularization,
let's dive deeper into Logistic Regression
and see why it's important to use regularization.
Suppose we want to predict the outcomes of coin flips.
We all know that for a fair coin,
the expected value is 50 percent of heads and 50 percent tails.
What if we had instead an unfair coin,
with a bend in it.
Now, let's say we want to generalize coin flip prediction to all coins,
fair and unfair, big and small,
heavy and light, et cetera.
What features could we use to predict whether a flip would be heads or tails?
Perhaps we could use the angle of the bend because it distributes X percent of mass in
the other dimension and/or creates a difference in
rotation due to air resistance or center of mass.
The mass of the coin might also be a good feature to know,
as well as size, properties such as diameter, thickness, et cetera.
We could use some feature engineering on this to get
the volume of the coin and, furthermore, the density.
Maybe the type of material or
materials the coin is composed of would be useful information.
These features would be pretty easy to measure.
However, they're only one side of the coin, pun intended.
The rest comes down to the action of the flip itself
such as how much a linear and angular velocity the coin was given,
the angle of launch,
the angle of what it lands on,
wind speed, et cetera.
These might be a bit harder to measure.
Now that we have all of these features,
what's the simplest model we could use to predict heads or tails?
Linear regression, of course.
What could go wrong with this choice though?
Our labels are heads or tails,
or thought of it in another way,
heads or not heads,
which could represent with the [inaudible] encoding of one for heads and zero for not heads.
But if we use linear regression with a standard mean squared error loss function,
our predictions could end up being outside the range of zero and one.
What does it mean if we predict 2.75 for the coin flip state?
That makes no sense.
A model that minimizes squared error is under
no constraint to treat as a probability in zero to one,
but this is what we need here.
In particular, you can imagine a model that predicts values less
than zero or greater than one for some new examples.
This would mean we can't use this model as a probability.
Simple tricks like capping their predictions at zero or one would introduce bias.
So we need something else,
in particular, a new loss function.
Converting this from linear progression to logistic regression can solve this dilemma.
From an earlier course of ours,
we went through the history of ML and used the sigmoid activation function.
Let's take a deeper look into that now.
The sigmoid activation function essentially takes the weighted sum, W transpose X,
plus B from a linear regression and instead of
just outputting that and then calculating the means squared error loss,
we change the activation function from linear to sigmoid which takes
that as an argument and squashes it smoothly between zero and one.
The input into the sigmoid,
normally the output of linear regression,
is called the logit.
So, we are performing a nonlinear transformation on our linear model.
Notice how the probability asymptotes to zero when the logits
go to negative infinity and to one when the logits go to positive infinity.
What does this imply for training?
Unlike mean squared error,
the sigmoid never guesses 1.0 or 0.0 probability.
This means that in gradient descents
constant drive to get the loss closer and closer to zero,
it will drive the weights closer and closer to plus or
minus infinity in the absence of regularization,
which can lead to problems.
First though, how can we interpret the output of a sigmoid?
Is it just some function that range is zero to one,
of which there are many, or is it something more?
The good news is it is something more;
it's a calibrated probability estimate.
Beyond just the range,
the sigmoid function is the cumulative distribution function
of the logistic probability distribution,
whose quantile function is the inverse of the logit which models the log odds.
Therefore, mathematically, the opposite of a sigmoid can be considered probabilities.
In this way, we can think of calibration as
the fact the outputs are real world values like probabilities.
This is in contrast to uncalibrated outputs like
an embedding vector which is internally
informative but the values have no real correlation.
Lots of output activation functions,
in fact, an infinite number,
could give you a number between zero and one but only this sigmoid is
proven to be a calibrated estimate of the training dataset probability of occurrence.
Using this fact about the sigmoid activation function,
we can cast binary classification problems into probabilistic problems.
For instance, instead of a model just predicting a yes or no such as,
will a customer buy an item,
it can now predict the probability that a customer buys an item.
This, paired with a threshold,
can provide a lot more predictive power than just a simple binary answer.
So now that we have calculated logistical regressions output
to some calibrated probability between zero and one,
how can we find our error and use that to update our weights through back propagation?
We use a loss function called cross-entropy,
which is also the Log Loss.
Unlike mean squared error,
there is less emphasis on errors where the output is relatively
close to the label where it's almost linear compared to quadratic.
However, also unlike mean squared error,
cross-entropy grows exponentially when the prediction is close to the opposite the label.
In other words, there is a very high penalty when the model not
only gets it wrong but does so with very high confidence.
Furthermore, the derivative of mean squared error could cause problems with training.
As we push the output closer and closer to zero or one,
and the gradient which is the output times one minus the output,
becomes smaller and smaller and changes the weights less and less.
Training could completely stall.
However, the gradient across entropy is
a logistic function times 1 minus logistic function,
which conveniently cancels out during back propagation,
therefore, not having that problem.
However, regularization is important in logistic regression
because driving loss to zero is difficult and dangerous.
First, as gradient descent seeks to minimize cross-entropy,
it pushes output values closer to one for
positive labels and closer to zero for negative labels.
Due to the equation of the sigmoid,
the function asymptotes to zero when the logic is negative infinity,
and to one when the logic is positive infinity.
To get the logits to negative or positive infinity,
imagine the weights is increased and increased leading to numerical stability problems,
overflows, and under flows.
This is dangerous and can ruin our training.
Also, near the asymptotes,
as you can see from the graph,
the sigmoid function becomes flatter and flatter.
This means that the derivative is getting closer and closer to zero.
Since we use the derivative and back propagation to update the weights,
it is important for the gradient not to become zero,
or else, training will stop.
This is called saturation,
when all activations end up in these plateaus which
leads to a vanishing gradient problem and makes training difficult.
This is also potentially useful insight here.
Imagine you assign a unique ID for each example and map each ID to its own feature.
If you use unregularized logistical regression,
this will lead to absolute overfitting.
As the model tries to drive loss to zero on all examples and never gets there,
the weights for each indicator feature will be driven
to positive infinity or negative infinity.
This can happen in practice,
in high dimensional data with feature crosses.
Often, there is a huge mass of rare crosses that happens only in one example each.
So, how can we protect ourselves from overfitting?
Which of these is important in performing logistic regression?
The correct answer is both A and B.
Adding regularization to logistic regression helps keep
the model simpler by having smaller parameter weights.
This penalty term added to the loss function makes
sure that cross-entropy through gradient descent doesn't keep
pushing the weights from closer to closer to
plus or minus infinity and causing numerical issues.
Also, with [inaudible] logits,
we can now stay in the less flat portions of
the sigmoid function making our gradients less close to zero,
and thus allowing weight updates and turning to continue.
C is incorrect, therefore,
so is E because regularization does
not transform the outputs in a calibrated probability estimate.
The great thing about logistic regression is that it already outputs
the calibrated property estimate since
the sigmoid function is
a cumulative distribution function of the logistic probability distribution.
This allows us to actually predict
probabilities instead of just binary answers like yes or no,
true or false, buy or sell, et cetera.
To counteract overfitting, we often do both regularization and early stopping.
For regularization model complexity increases with large weights,
and so as we tune and start to get larger larger weights for rarer and rarer scenarios,
we end up increasing the loss so we stop.
L2 regularization will keep the weight values smaller and
L1 regularization will keep the model sparser by dropping more features.
To find the optimal L1 and L2 hyperparameter choices during hyperperimeter tuning,
you're searching for the point in
the validation loss function where you obtain the lowest value.
At that point, any less regularization increases your variance,
starts overfitting and hurts generalization
and any more regularization increases your bias,
starts underfitting and it hurts your generalization.
Early stoppings stops training when overfitting begins.
As you train your model,
you should evaluate your model on your validation data set,
every so many steps, epics, minutes etc.
As training continues, both the training error,
and the validation error should be decreasing but at
some point the validation error might begin to actually increase.
It is at this point that the model is beginning to memorize the training data set,
and lose its ability to generalize to the validation data set and most
importantly to the new data that we will eventually want to use this model four.
Using early stopping, would stop the model at this point and then back
up and use the weights from
the previous step before it hit validation error and function point.
Here, the loss is just L(w,
D) i.e. no regularization term.
Interestingly, early stopping is an approximate equivalent of
L2 regularization and it is often used
in its place because it is competitionally cheaper.
Fortunately, in practice we always use both as
Epoch regularization L1 and L2 and also some amount of early stopping regularization.
Even though L2 regularization and early stopping seem a bit redundant,
for liberal sytems, you may not quite choose
the optimal hyperparameters and thus early stopping can help fix that choice for you.
It's great that we can obtain a probability from our logistic regression model.
However, at the end of the day sometimes
users just want a simple decision to be made for them,
for their real world problems.
Should the email be sent to the spam folder or not,
Should the loan be approved or not,
which road should we route the user through.
How can we use our probability estimate to help
the tool using our model to make a decision?
We choose a threshold.
A simple threshold of a binary classification problem
would be all probabilities less than or equal to
50 percent should be a no and all probability is greater than 50 percent should be a yes.
However, for certain real world problems,
we weigh them on a different split,
like 60-40, 20-80, 19-91.
Etc. Depending on how we want our balance of our type one and type two errors,
on other words our balance of false positives and false negatives.
For binary classification, we will have four possible outcomes;
true positives, true negatives,
false positives, and false negatives.
Combinations of these values can lead to evaluation metrics like precision,
which is the number of true positives divided by all positives and
recall which is the number of true positives divided
by the sum of true positives and false negatives,
which gives the sensitivity or true positive rate.
You can tune your choice of threshold to optimize the metric of your choice.
Is there any easy way to help us do this?
A Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve or ROC curve for short,
shows how a given Malos predictions create different true positive
versus false positive rates when different decision thresholds are used.
As we lower the threshold we are likely to have more false positives,
but will also increase the number of true positives we find.
Ideally, a perfect model would have zero false positives and zero false negatives
which plugging that into the equations would give
a true positive rate of one and a false positive rate of zero.
To create a curve, we would pick each possible decision threshold and re-evaluate.
Each threshold value creates a single point but by
evaluating many thresholds eventually a curve is formed.
Fortunately there is an efficient sorting based algorithm to do this.
Each mile would create a different ROC curve.
So how can we use these curves to compare the relative performance of our models when
we don't know exactly what decision threshold we want to use?
We can use the area under the curve as
an aggregate measure performance across all possible classification thresholds.
AUC helps you choose between models when
you don't know what your system threshold is going to be ultimately used.
It's like asking, if we pick a random positive and a random
negative what's the probability my model scores them in the correct relative order?
The nice thing about AUC is that its scale and
variant and classification threshold and variant.
People like to use it for those reasons.
People sometimes also use AUC for the precision recall curve,
or more recently and precision recall gain curves,
which just use different combinations of
the four production outcomes as metrics along the axes.
However, treating this only as an aggregate measure can mask some effects.
For example, a small improvement in AUC might come by doing a better job of
ranking very unlikely negatives as even still yet more unlikely.
Which is fine, but potentially not materially beneficial.
When evaluating our logistic regression models,
we need to make sure predictions are unbiased.
When we talk about bias in this sense,
we are not talking about the bias term in the models linear equation.
Instead we mean there should be
an overall shift in either the positive or negative direction.
A simple way to check the prediction bias is compare
the average value predictions made by the model,
over a dataset, to the average value of the labels in that data set.
If they are not relatively close,
then you might have a problem.
Bias is like a canary in the mine,
where we can use it as an indicator of something being wrong.
If you have bias,
you definitely have a problem.
But even zero bias alone,
does not mean everything in your system is perfect,
but it is a great sanity check.
If you have bias,
you could have an incomplete feature set,
a buggy pipeline, a biased training sample, etc.
You can look for bias in slices of data,
which can help guide improvements of removing bias from your model.
Let's look at an example of how you can do that.
Here's a calibration plot from the simple experiment browser.
You'll notice that this isn't a log log scale.
As we're comparing the bucketed log odds predicted to the bucketed log odds observed.
You'll note that things are pretty well calibrated in the moderate range,
but the extreme low end is pretty bad.
This can happen in parts the data's base is not well represented or
because of noise or because of overly strong reservation.
The bucketing can be done in a couple of ways;
you can bucket it by literally breaking up
the target predictions or we can bucket it by quantiles.
Why do we need to bucket prediction
to make calibration plots in predicting probabilities?
For any given event, the true label is either 0 or one.
For example, not clicked or clicked.
But our prediction values will always be a probabilistic guess
somewhere in the middle like 0.1 or 0.33.
For any individual example, we're always off.
But if you group enough examples together,
we'd like to see that on average the sum of the true zeros
and ones is about the same as a mean probability we're predicting.
Which of these is important performing Logistic regression.
The correct answer is all of the above.
It is extremely important that our model generalizes,
so that we have the best predictions and new data
which is the entire reason we create them all to begin with.
To help do this, it is important that we do not overfed our data.
Therefore, adding in penalty terms to the objective function like with
L1 regularization for sparsity and L2 regularization for keeping model width small,
and adding early stopping can help in this regard.
It is also important to choose a tuned threshold for
deciding what decisions to make when your probability estimate outputs.
To minimize or maximize the business metric is important to you.
If this isn't well-defined,
then we can use more statistical means,
such as calculating the number of true and false positives and negatives,
and combine them into different metrics,
such as the true and false positive rates.
We can then repeat this process for
many different thresholds and then plot the area under
the curve or AUC to come up with a relative aggregate measure of model performance.
Lastly, it's important in our predictions are unbiased,
and even if there isn't bias we should be still
diligent to make sure our model is performing well.
We begin looking for bias by making sure that
the average of the predictions is very close to the errors observations.
A helpful way to find where bias might be hiding is to look at slices of data and
use something like a calibration plot to isolate
the problem areas for further refinement.