In this lab,
we take a previously developed TensorFlow
model to predict taxi fare rides, and
package it up so that it can be run
on Cloud Machine Learning Engine.
For now we'll run this
on a small data set.
The model that was developed
is rather simplistic, and
therefore the accuracy of
the model's not great either.
However, this lab will illustrate
the basics of running TensorFlow models
on Cloud ML.
Specifically, we'll cover how to
package up a TensorFlow model,
run training locally,
run training on Cloud,
deploy the model to Cloud, and
invoke the model to carry out predictions.
Practice the lab yourself by reading
through the notebook comments and
executing the code cells.
I encourage you to edit the code to ensure
you understand what each part does.
And then come back to the wrap up video,
where we'll walk through it together.