tf.expand_dims is a way of changing
the shape by inserting a dimension of 1 into a tensor shape.
So, we have x, which is a 3/2 matrix.
When we call tf.expand_dims on x,
we specify which dimension we want to insert a new thing at.
We say one, which in Python means a second place,
0 will mean first place.
So, the expanded shape changes from 3,
2 to 3, 1, 2.
What does this actually mean?
The original value of x,
which is a neat 3/2 matrix now becomes a 3D matrix, a 3D tensor.
Notice the number of opening square brackets.
There is no change to the actual numbers that are stored.
We have already looked at slicing.
So, this is a way of extracting part of a tensor,
but we looked at the shortcut syntax of simply specifying its square brackets,
the rows and columns we wanted.
tf.slice is a long form way of doing that.
We are asking tf.slice here to pull data out of x.
We're telling it to start at position 0,
1 and pull out two rows and one column.
So, do you understand why you get the numbers 2 and 5?
It's a quick quiz.
How would you write the tf.slice call here in terms of the square brackets syntax?
Answer, x square bracket,
the rows that you want are 0-2,
so 0 and 1 and the columns that you want are 1-2 so just 1.
Squeeze is the inverse operation to expand dims.
Expand dims lets you insert a dimension of size one anywhere within the tensor.
Squeeze lets you remove dimensions of size one from the shape of a tensor.
So, here I have a tensor that's a 3D tensor.
Note the number of square brackets.
T is a 3D tensor.
I call squeeze passing in t and I get back a 2D tensor that's more compact.
The original tensor had the shape 1/2/4 and the squeeze tensor has the shape just 2/4.
To be sure, you don't really need expand dims and squeeze,
you can simply use reshape,
but your code will be a bit more self-explanatory if you explain that you're inserting or
removing a dimension one to convert the scalars to tensors are basically dealing with 1,
2/4 matrix as either a 3D tensor of shape,
1/2/4 or as a 2D tensor of shape 2/4 depending on the context of the code.