In the previous few lessons, we talked
about how you can debug a TensorFlow
program by looking at the error message,
isolating the method in question,
feeding it fake data, and then fixing the
error once we understand what's going on.
Sometimes, though,
the problems are more subtle.
They only happen when
specific things happen.
And you may not be able to identify
why things are working for five, six,
seven batches, and
then all of a sudden you get an error, and
then things will go back to normal.
In other words,
when the errors are associated with some
specific input value or
condition of the execution system.
At that point, you need to debug
the full-blown program, and
there are three methods to do this.
tf.Print() is a way to print
out the values of tensors when
specific conditions are met.
tfdbg is an interactive debugger
that you can run from a terminal and
attach to a local or
remote TensorFlow session.
TensorBoard is a visual monitoring tool.
We talked about this as a way
to look at the tag, but
there's more kinds of troubleshooting
that you can do with TensorBoard.
You can look at evaluation metrics,
look for over-fitting,
layers that are dead, etc.
Higher level debugging of neural networks,
in other words.
We look at TensorBoard in a future
chapter of this course, ubt for
now I just wanted to drop in
a placeholder so you know and
you keep in mind that TensorBoard
is a powerful troubleshooting tool.
One sort of of silly thing but
worth mentioning,
the default level in terms of logging for
TensorFlow programs is WARN.
So it runs sort of quiet.
Change the log level to INFO to see many
more log messages as TensorFlow trains.
You can change the log level
by using tf.logging and
setting the verbosity level.
The levels are debug, info, warn,
error, and fatal, in that order.
Debug is the most verbose, and
fatal is the most quiet, info
is what I tend to use in development, and
warn is what I tend to use in production.
Of course, you can set up a command line
parameter to switch from one to the other.
tf.Print can be used to log
specific tensor values.
Perhaps you're dividing a by b and
you're getting NAN, not a number,
NAN, in the output and
you want to figure out the value of a and
the value of b that's causing the problem.
Well, if you print a, you would only
get the debug output of the tensor,
you won't get its value.
Lazy execution, remember, you have to
evaluate a tensor to get its value, so
you don't want to print the value
of a every single time.
The idea here is a print_ab is a tensor,
it wraps s and prints out a and b.
I then replace s in the graph by print_ab
only for those batches where s is NAN.
Ergo, only those things get printed.
This has to be done in
a standalone program,
because Datalab consumes the tensor for
log messages.
Hence my workaround of writing the code
to a file and then running it.
You tend to use tf.Print on
running TensorFlow programs
to diagnose rare errors, and
make sure to capture things in the logs.
It's a neat trick.
TensorFlow also has a dynamic
interactive debugger called tf_debug.
You run it from the command line.
So you run the TensorFlow program from
a terminal as a standalone program.
And then when you run it, you would
add the command line flag --debug.
This is also helpful to debug
remotely running TensorFlow programs,
in other words,
you can attach to the program.
There are also special debug hooks for
debugging experiment and
estimator programs.
And once a program starts, you can use
a debugger to step through the code,
set break points, etc.
If you've ever used
an interactive debugger for
any other language or environment,
the terminology, steps, break points,
etc., they should all be pretty familiar.