Let's first address generalization,
which help us answer the question about when
the most accurate ML model is not always your best choice?
Once again here we find ourselves with the familiar natality dataset,
but this time we're going to use the mother's weight gain on
the X-axis to predict the duration of the pregnancy,
there on the Y-axis.
What do you observe about the pattern that you see in the data?
It looks very strongly correlated,
the more weight gained, the longer the duration of the pregnancy,
which intuitively kind of makes sense as the baby is growing.
To model this behavior and prove a correlation,
what model would you typically want to call on first?
If you said a linear regression model,
you are exactly correct.
So, as we covered for regression problems,
the loss metric that you want to optimize for,
is typically mean squared error,
MSE or RMSE, the root mean squared error.
Mean squared error tells us how close a regression line is to the set of points from it.
It does this by taking those distances from the points to the actual regression line.
And those distances are called the errors and then it squares them.
And the squaring is necessary to remove any negative signs.
And MSE also gives more weight to those larger differences from the line.
Taking the square root of the MSE gives us the RMSE which is simply the distance
on average of a data point from the fitted line measured along a vertical line.
The RMSE is directly interpreted in terms of the measurement units on the Y-axis.
So, it's a better measure of goodness of fit than a correlation coefficient.
Now, for both error measures,
a lower value indicates a better performing model,
and the closer the error is to zero the better.
Here, we're using a linear regression model,
which simply draws that line of best fit to minimize the error.
Our final RMSE is 2.224.
And let's say for our problem, that's pretty good.
All right, but look at this.
What if you used a more complex model?
A more complex model could have more free parameters.
In this case, these free parameters let us capture
every single squiggle in that dataset as you see there.
While we reduce our RMSE all the way down to zero,
the model is now perfectly accurate.
Are we done?
Is this the best model?
Can we productionalize this?
Well, people and you might feel there's something fishy going on with model number two.
But how can we tell? In ML,
we often have lots of data and no such intuition.
Is a neural network with eight nodes better than a neural network with 12 nodes?
We have a lower RMSE for one with 16 nodes. Should we pick that one?
Example here that you see might be a polynomial of
the hundredth order or a neural network with hundreds of nodes.
As you saw in the spiral example,
at the end of the last lecture on optimization,
a more complex model has more of these parameters that can be optimized.
Models can help fit more complex data like a spiral,
it also might help it memorize simpler smaller datasets.
So, at what point do we say to a model,
stop training you're memorizing the dataset and possibly overfitting?
Now, one of the best ways to assess the quality of a model is to see how
it performs well against a new dataset that it hasn't seen before.
Then we can determine whether or not that model generalizes well across new data points.
It's a good proxy for production of real world data.
So, let's check back on the linear regression model and
the neural network models and see how they're doing now.
Our linear regression model on these new data points,
is generalizing pretty well.
Our RMSE is comparable to what we saw
before and in this case no surprises is a good thing.
We want consistent performance out of our models across training and validation.
So, looking back at model two, we can see that it doesn't generalize well at all,
on the new training design and this is really alarming.
The RMSE jumped from 0 to 3.2,
which is a huge problem and indicates that the model was
completely overfitting itself on the training data set that
it was provided and that proved to be too brittle or not generalizable to new data.
Now, you may be asking, how can I make sure that my model is not overfitting?
How do I know when to stop training?
And the answer is surprisingly simple,
we are going to split your data.
Now, by dividing your original dataset into completely separated and isolated groups,
you can either retrain your model and train it
on the training dataset and then once you're done with training,
compare its performance against an independent siloed validation dataset.
And models that generalized well,
we'll have similar loss metrics or error values across training and validation.
And as soon as you start seeing your models not
perform well against your validation data set,
like if your loss metrics start to increase or creep up,
it's time to stop.
Training and evaluating ML models experiment with finding
the right generalizable model and
model parameters that fit your training dataset without memorizing.
As you see here, we have
an overly simplistic linear model that doesn't fit the relationships true to the data.
You can see how bad it is almost visually.
Right? There's quite a few points outside the shape of that trend line.
This is called underfitting.
On the opposite end of the spectrum and slightly
even more dangerous is overfitting as we talked about.
This is shown on the right extreme.
Here we've greatly increased the complexity of our linear model interpreted to
an nth order polynomial which seems to help
the model and fit the data and all of the squiggles that we were talking about earlier.
So, this is where your evaluation dataset comes into play,
and you're going to determine if the model parameters are leading to overfitting.
Is it too complex?
And overfitting or memorized in that training dataset can be often
far worse than having a model that only adequately fits your data.
Sometimes you might not know until production,
that's what we validated.
Somewhere in between an underfit and an overfit is the right level of model complexity.
So, let's look at how we are going to use our validation dataset
to help us know when to stop training and to prevent overfitting.