Now that we know about all these nodes and
levers,
how do we set them in [INAUDIBLE] code?
Let's have a close look
at some sample code.
We control the batchsize,
we have the input function, the learning
rate is a parameter of the optimizer
algorithm, in this case, FtrlOptimizer.
Regularization rate is also a parameter
of the optimizer algorithm.
Once they define the optimizer,
we pass it to the estimator object.
In this case, an instance of the linear
regressive class of estimators.
Instead of setting number of epochs,
you need to define number of steps.
This is because number of epochs is not
failure-friendly in distributed training.
You need to adjust number of steps
based on batchsize and learning rate.
For instance, if you want to process for
100 epochs and you have a 1,000 examples,
then for a batchsize of 1,000,
number of steps would be 100.
For a batchsize of 100,
number of steps would be 1,000.
Basically, number of steps equal number
of epochs multiplied by number of
examples divided by batchsize.
And remember, if you decrease the learning
rate, you'll have to train for
more epochs.