So, pick two use cases from the following two slides,
use cases that you're somewhat familiar with,
and you're going to cast this in three different ways.
First, cast it as a machine learning problem,
what is being predicted,
what data is needed.
Second, cast it as a software problem.
What is the API for the problem during production?
Who will use the service?
How were they doing it today?
And finally, cast it in the framework of a data problem.
What are some key actions to collect,
analyze, predict, and react to the data or predictions?
Remembering that different input features might require different kinds of actions.
So, here is a first set of potential use cases.
Freeze this frame of the video and pick a problem to work on,
whether it's in manufacturing or it's in retail or it's healthcare and life sciences.
Here is the second set of use cases again freeze the video and pick a use case to
work on whether it's travel and hospitality or
financial services or energy and utilities.
Having done that having picked the two use cases,
switch over to the lab and take some time to answer the questions in the lab.
Go to the student forums,
discuss your answers with other students and then when you're done,
also check out my answer to these questions.